parentmap.com 2011-10-02

# Our Online Privacy Policy - ParentMap.com

You know and trust _ParentMap_ newsmagazine and parentmap.com, and we value that trust. We are committed to maintaining the privacy of all personal information that you provide. The following policy describes the privacy practices of _ParentMap_ ("we" or "us"). You should read this policy in order to understand how we treat the information you provide to us as you use our Web site.

**Information we collect**

We receive information in several ways:  
•    You may have subscribed to our magazine or newsletter.  
•    You may have filled out a “Contact Information” form when visiting our booth at an event.  
•    You may have asked to receive information in the past.  
•    You may be an advertiser.   
•    You may be a present or past sponsor of a ParentMap event.  
•    You may be a subscriber to one of our e-newsletters.  
•    You may enter to win one of our giveaways.

We may collect the following information:  
•    Your name  
•    Your address  
•    Your email address  
•    Your phone number  
•    How many children you have  
•    The birth years of your children

 _ParentMap_ does not request any other personal information and will not collect such information unless you provide it to us.

**How we use the information collected**

If you submit personal information to us through our Web site, we may use that information to operate and maintain the Web site. For example, the information we collect allows us to send you information via email on upcoming events that may be of interest to you and your family. It allows us to send notifications about anything new and exciting at _ParentMap_ newsmagazine or parentmap.com. We may occasionally conduct online surveys and want to offer you the opportunity to participate, if you choose to. The information also allows us to provide advertisers and potential advertisers with aggregate information about our user base and usage patterns.

We also use certain non-personally-identifiable information, such as anonymous cookies, IP address and browser type, to improve the quality and design of our Web site; to create new features, functionality and services by storing and analyzing user preferences and trends; and to further our efforts to police the Web site and enforce our Terms of Use.

**Cookies**

When you visit our Web site, it may pass cookies to your computer. A cookie is a string of information that is sent by a Web site and stored on your hard drive or temporarily in your computer's memory, so that the site can deliver content appropriate for you. We may use cookies to (a) monitor our marketing campaigns; (b) monitor statistics relating to the Web site; (c) track your submissions and status in promotions; and (d) police the Web site and enforce the Terms of Use. Google, as a third party vendor, also uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Users may opt out of the use of Google's cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

 **Who we may share information with**

We keep your personally identifiable information confidential and we generally do not disclose it, with the following exceptions:

  * We share information we collect on our Web site with the _ParentMap_ team. Our employees have access to some of your personally identifiable information for the purpose of helping us run our business. They access and use such data on a “need to know” basis confidentially. The _ParentMap_ team may use this information to invite you to events or introduce you to services that may be of interest to you. 
  * We may share information from giveaways with carefully selected business partners that provide prizes to _ParentMap_. These companies and organizations may use the information we share to provide you with special opportunities and offers. Also, contest winners may be asked to provide information such as physical address and phone number to prize providers for prize fulfillment purposes.
  * Our Web site may also share information with companies that provide support services to us (such as a mailing host or printer). These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions. These companies are not authorized to use the information we share with them for any other purpose. 
  * We may disclose information you provide to our Web site when we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law or to protect the rights, property, or safety of our Web site, our users, or others.

Also, any information that you include in a comment to our Web site, particularly the blog, may be redistributed through the Internet and other media channels and may be viewed by the general public. The information contained in a comment may be viewable by all users of the Web site. IF YOU CHOOSE TO MAKE ANY OF YOUR PERSONAL OR OTHER INFORMATION PUBLICLY AVAILABLE THROUGH THE WEB SITE, YOU DO SO AT YOUR OWN RISK.

 **Third-party Advertisers, Links to Other Sites**

We allow third-party advertisers to advertise on our Web site. These advertisers may use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Web site. These advertisers automatically receive your IP address when this happens, and they may use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content you see. Advertisers also may use information regarding your use of the Web site, such as the number of times you viewed an ad (but not any personally identifiable information), to determine which ads to deliver to you.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party advertisers for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. This privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. Any data obtained by third-party advertisers that is subsequently shared with us is maintained and dealt with by us consistent with this privacy policy.

 **What choices do I have?**

 **Emails**

If you provide our Web site with your email address, you may receive emails from us. You can discontinue these emails by cancelling your subscription to these services.  If you would like to update your information with _ParentMap_ or unsubscribe from our list, click the "unsubscribe/update your profile" link provided in our newsletters. If we ever send you information by email concerning new products or services that you did not expressly request, we will provide you with an email address by which you may request no future notices. At any time, you can contact us through [email ](mailto:feedback@parentmap.com)to have your contact preference changed to “Do Not Contact.”

 **Sharing with other companies**

If you do not want us to share your email address with carefully selected business partners outside of _ParentMap_ , do not enter a giveaway through our Web site.

 **Security**

We take reasonable steps to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. But you should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. Personal information, once collected, generally is not shown on our Web site. Exceptions to this rule include (a) when you click on the “unsubscribe” or “manage preferences” link in an email, our third-party mailing host may display your information so that you can update it and (b) when you include personally identifiable information in a comment to the Web site, such as a comment to a blog post.

**No guarantees**

While this privacy policy states standards for the collection and maintenance of personal information, and while commercially reasonable efforts will be made to meet these standards, we do not guarantee that we will comply with these standards. There may be factors beyond our control that may result in disclosure of data. Consequently, we offer no warranties or representations regarding the maintenance or non-disclosure of personal information.

**Privacy policy changes**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any changes here, and the revised privacy policy will be effective as of the date that it is posted.

 **Contact us**

If you have any questions about our policies, please contact us:

ParentMap  
PMB #399  
4742 42nd Ave SW  
Seattle, WA 98116-4553  
206-709-9026  

---|---|---
